Hello in the previous video we talked about amdahl's law
The one where it's limiting the speed up right because of the sequential
Lights off
Software out of our program
In this video we will talk about another law concerning parallel program
The lowest called Gustav's law
And it's kind of
Twists around
The problem of limited speed
So we can get a linear speed up it basically States
That is true that we are restrict
Addicted by the sequential part of our software
Write the speed
What's restricted by that
However if we
Take into account
That we can also increase
Our problem
We can have a linear speed
With regards
Listen to the processing
So for example
If we go back to our example of building
At war with builders
What we can do is to get those people to do
Different jobs in a different
Parts right for example
By asking them to build a
In a different place right where another wheelbarrow is available
In this way we have increased
What's the problem
How to fix the size wall
The wall is now
Bigger
Lights in a different location as well
But the idea here is that we have in
The problem
And now in the same time
End the time of 2 days we have finished three walls instead of
Of course the problem is that you might not want to have three walls right but if you have
Those extra
Just doing nothing might as well get them to do something
Get them to build a garden shed
Play something else
But the whole idea here is that you increase the problem
Much bigger so we can scale it
Is better
This kind of relation between the problem size and the number of
Off processors
Putin is known as the gustafson's
And it's kind of a more positive take
On andalus
And it's also applies to computer programs imagine for example you were writing a computer game and you
I have a fast video card
That has maybe I don't know
Processors on
And you realize that
No matter how many processors
You are putting
On your rendering part you can never get
The frame
What is higher than 60 Fram
So what do you do is use only half of those processors the frame rate
Is unaffected
However you use the other
To do other things for example Maybe
Increase the resolution
Or increase number of polygons or
Improve your
And what is he over here is that as long as you increase the problem size right as long as you have an infinite
Problem
Can you increase the number of processors
It doesn't really matter
How much of
Software is linear and how much
Is parlor
Because the relation is always
Linear
The speed up of course will be slower okay if you have a
Spiral
Algorithm
Your speed up will increase slower
However
It
Linear as long as you keep on increasing your problem
It's also important to realize
What's concurrent programming or parallel programming
Just about speeding things
Sometimes
It's convenient to program in a multithreaded
In fact in the next lecture in the next
And the one after we will look
Cat implementing a simulation
Assimilation that mimics
Bird Behavior right the flights
The birds in flight
And we will see that it's much easier to implement
Buy modeling each bird as if it was a separate thread
Play the ASAP red process
The other thing to consider is that part of the programming or Some people prefer to call it concurrent programming
That's not just make sense when you have more than one
Process
Typically when you have more than one processor us sign
In a task
We each processor
And when that completes
You swap it out
And you replace it with another one and you keep on
Doing this over and over again does it make sense to use part of the programming when you have only one core when you have
Only one processor
If you only have one person what you can do is that while
Add process is being executed and you interrupted
And you swap
With
And if you do this fast enough and you do it
Continuously you would give the impression that you have multiple processes running
This is sometimes useful when you want to have your program more responsive right when you want them to respond to
External
When's when they happen in
Maybe you know a few minutes later
This swapping in and out of these processors or thread
That's not just happen
To give the impression of conc
Sometimes a process
Does needs to perform some I
And what happens is
Instead of just having the procedure
Waiting for
That data to arrive from hard disk for example which was slow
Things down quite a lot
What do you do with the stop the execution of that program let's wait for
What's IO operation to complete and in the meantime you put another process that it's ready to execute
Can you put it on the CPU and you continue executing that
Eventually when the io completes
What's the process will go back
Back to our ridicu
And then
Eventually it will get its turn to
Turn on the CPU
Now that we know
Theory about parallel
And we have seen
We want to de
Off
This multi
Sing or
What we will do in the next lesson
Is to look
Add some of the more practical to
That will allow us to program our
Software
So join me
In the next lesson to learn
More about multi