Hello and welcome
The score is called multi treading in goal
A thread is simply the stool or this abstraction
That allows us to perform
Parallel computation
Computing is the
Or Some people prefer
I have to call it
Where you can have this one problem and throw different
Processing units at it
So we can solve it faster and quick
This whole course is about learning how to do that
It's about learning how we can program
He's a special types of algorithms
So we can solve
Problems quick
Now
To start my courses with the more difficult or the more theoretical
Off the subject
And this is what we will do now we will examine some of the properties and the laws surrounding
Parallel computing
In order to understand the laws and
It's around
For the computing
Let's make use of a simple example
Imagine for example you hire a builder to build you a fence right a brick
Fence and after you hire this Builder he sits on his job and in 8 days he manages to
Build this fans or this
Now imagine that
You wanted to be
A little faster you might hire to builders instead of one and instead of it being finished in 8 days it's now finished
Just in
But what if you hire for people
Now you have bad things up even further
And the wall has been built in
What's 3 days you decide to hire even more people in this example you have hired
And now you have finished the job in Just 2
As you might expect there is a limit on how much time you can speed it up
Write the limit in this case is 2
You can never get the world
Much faster
Then
It's just by hiring more
If you have ever worked in a development team and this is probably familiar right
The project managers or the business owners
Besides to throw more developers at the project
Thinking that they will finish the project quicker
They might speed up things a little bit but
The speed up is not linear right
You cannot throw for example 1,000 developers on the same project
And expect it to be
1000 *
It's not going to work
In
Build the wall example you know we can build multiple walls in parallel right we can have different work
Where is building different parts of the world
Simultaneous
However because we have only
Wheelbarrow right to carry the brick
We can only have
If one person
Set the time using
Wheel
This is our bottl
If this was a program this would be the sequential part
Off our program
Only one person can carry the bricks we using this one
Wheel
So it's important to realize that each program will have
Parallel park
The one where we
Multiple process is working on
On that
And the sequential part right we're only
One process
And the ratio between this parallel and sequential part will dictate
The speed
Stop that we can a
This is called amdahl
And it's a property where we can arrive
If the speed
Depending on the ratio between the parallel and the sequent
Over here we have a few examples
What is each plot is
Is in different color for example the green one over here we have
If every show of 9525
Sequential right to 5% is
As you can
Even though we only have 5%
List
Particular program
Even when we have 256
Is processor is working on the same problem
We only achieve a speed up
Cancel about
The situation is worse
The sequential part is higher this red line over here for example is
75 percent parallel 25% sequent
The blue line over here is
The 50 % parallel
After you get a double speed
It will
Play pretty much the
Name no matter
How many process
However this is not the whole story
There's another parts
Do part of computing that is called
Gustav's
And we will examine this law in the next video